Well, I hope you had a bit of fun playing around with the sprites and the code blocks, because in
this lesson we are going to be exploring some of the code blocks together.
So let's begin with an important what is code?
Code is basically just a set of instructions for a computer.
You see, computers actually aren't very clever.
Well, they aren't very clever at figuring out what you mean, like humans are.
They need very clear and specific instructions, step by step, in order to do what we want them to
do.
Imagine you're telling someone how to make a sandwich for a human.
You might just say, please make me a peanut butter and jelly sandwich.
But for a computer, you would have to be much more specific.
Like take one slice of bread and place it on a plate.
Take the jar of peanut butter and open it.
Insert a knife and after getting some peanut butter, use the knife to spread it evenly on the bread.
Then take the jar of jelly.
Use a spoon to scoop some onto the other slice of bread.
Place the slice of bread on top of the peanut butter and so on.
You get the idea.
Another example is if we could look at the sprite we have, let's say we wanted to walk to the end of
the screen.
The computer will not understand what we mean if we just say, walk to the end of the screen.
However, what we can tell it is to move ten steps.
As you can see, the cat moves forward ten steps.
But still, it's not actually walking, it's just moving.
Okay, so what we can also do is change to the next costume.
Now if we click this, we can see that it looks like it is walking.
Now we're getting somewhere, but still it isn't walking to the end of the screen.
So what we could then do is grab this repeat block, put it over these blocks, and now it will basically
repeat all the code ten times.
Now if we click it, we can see it moves a lot further, but it's still not to the end of the screen.
So I can change the steps from 10 to 50.
Okay.
Now there we have it.
Our cat successfully walking to the other side of the screen.
So as you can see, while computers are incredibly powerful and can do amazing things, they need very
precise and specific instructions in order to make them work, because computers will do exactly what
you tell them to do and nothing more.
But ready yourself now, because in the next lesson, we will be officially coding.